<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rss version="2.0"
 xmlns:blogChannel="http://backend.userland.com/blogChannelModule"
>

<channel>
<title>Bootpolish: blog</title>
<link>http://www.bootpolish.net/pageloader.pl?page=home_blog</link>
<description>Sorry, no site description at this time</description>
<language>en-uk</language>
<copyright>Copyright Bootpolish.net</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat Jun 28 20:04:46 2008</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Sat Jun 28 20:04:46 2008</lastBuildDate>
<managingEditor>cjr@bootpolish.net</managingEditor>
<webMaster>cjr@bootpolish.net</webMaster>

<item>
<title>The Importance of Microsoft</title>
<description>
It sometimes seems that everyone in the Linux world hates Microsoft.  I don&#x27;t have a problem with that.  What I do have a problem with, is that this hatred extends to any Linux project that dares to implement Microsoft technology on Linux.  Yes, of course, I am talking about `Mono`.  Speaking as someone who has put the Linux desktop into a company, I can tell you that the biggest problem for me was in dealing with mission-critical applications that are Windows-only.  The solution for us was {virtualising a Windows 2003 server|windows virtualisation} - Microsoft wins again.

I know, it&#x27;s our fault for choosing Windows software, well, here&#x27;s a newsflash, most software is written for Windows, and there aren&#x27;t always Linux alternatives.  You show me Linux-compatible motor-trade software or Linux-compatible filling-station software.  You can&#x27;t - they doesn&#x27;t exist.  But - and here&#x27;s the crunch - I can show you .net applications in both those markets.

So for me, the equation is simple - implement .net on Linux - and you make it a whole lot easier for businesses to adopt Linux on the desktop.

Business is critical for Linux, because people are most familiar with the operating system that they use at work; if that happens to be Linux, then they are infinitely more likely to adopt Linux at home.  Once Linux is in the home, then the whole family and, most importantly their children, are likely to adopt Linux.  Thus the Linux snowball starts gaining momentum at last.

Once there are a significant proportion of Linux users on the desktop, then developers will start to worry about cross-platform, making it even easier to adopt Linux.

</description>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bootpolish.net/pageloader.pl?page=home_blog#24/06/2008: The Importance of Microsoft</guid>
<pubDate>Tue Jun 24 00:00:00 2008</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LTSP Scanning</title>
<description>
Since upgrading to LTSP5, our scanning has ceased to work.  I have created a Work in Progress page called LTSP5 Scanning.  Having worked through the instructions contained on that page, scanning is still not working.  The logs show that the request &#x22;scanimage -L&#x22; is being detected by the client and the client is confirming that the LTSP server has permission, but it is then failing with:

&#x3C;pre&#x3E;
Jun 24 12:16:55 juno scanimage: unable to open /var/run/hplip/hpssd.port: No such file or directory: prnt/hpijs/hplip_api.c 94
Jun 24 12:16:55 juno scanimage: unable to connect hpssd socket 50002: Connection refused: prnt/hpijs/hplip_api.c 719
&#x3C;/pre&#x3E;

Not realising that HP had any involvement in scanning on Linux, I assumed that this was a port conflict with some utilities installed on our HP server, but reading into the matter further I believe that this is because the client has detected that the scanner is an HP model and has attempted to run an HP scan utility that is not installed on the client.  Just guesses, if you have any ideas, please contact me.  Any useful messages will be posted here!

</description>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bootpolish.net/pageloader.pl?page=home_blog#24/06/2008: LTSP Scanning</guid>
<pubDate>Tue Jun 24 00:00:00 2008</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Changes to web</title>
<description>
I have re-written the About LTSP webpage, to outline the benefits of LTSP over the Windows alternatives.  I have also renamed the Windows page to Windows for Linux and have moved it to the top level menu, as it was not specific to LTSP.

   * About LTSP
   * Windows for Linux

</description>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bootpolish.net/pageloader.pl?page=home_blog#24/06/2008: Changes to web</guid>
<pubDate>Tue Jun 24 00:00:00 2008</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LDM password expiry problem</title>
<description>
I have had my first user&#x27;s password expire since our LTSP5 Upgrade.

   * User enters username and hits enter
   * User enters password and hits enter
   * LDM tells user password has expired enter new password
   * User enters new password and hits enter
   * LDM tells user to verify password
   * User enters new password again and hits enter

And then it enters a crazy loop where it just continually prompts for the password.  If you reboot the client you start from the beginning again, so clearly the password change has not been accepted.  I confidently told user that he had obviously entered his password incorrectly - I then rebooted the client and did exactly the same myself.  I believe this could be a bug, and I suspect it may be related to the following thread:

   * {ldm problems with debian etch|http://marc.info/?t=121069447400001&#x26;r=1&#x26;w=2}

I have created this issue in my work in progress section called ldm password expiry.

</description>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bootpolish.net/pageloader.pl?page=home_blog#24/06/2008: LDM password expiry problem</guid>
<pubDate>Tue Jun 24 00:00:00 2008</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>MD5 Checker</title>
<description>
Linux includes &#x22;md5sum&#x22; utility for checking MD5 values of downloaded applications.  I find it a nuisance having to drop into a command shell and execute...

&#x3C;pre&#x3E;
$ md5sum download.iso
&#x3C;/pre&#x3E;

... and then manually compare with the author&#x27;s.  I have therefore written a simple KDE ServiceMenu to add MD5 checking.

Simply download and extract to /home/~USERNAME~/.kde/share/apps/konqueror/servicemenus.

</description>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bootpolish.net/pageloader.pl?page=home_blog#23/06/2008: MD5 Checker</guid>
<pubDate>Mon Jun 23 00:00:00 2008</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mobile Phones</title>
<description>
Our MD has once again brought up the thorny subject of which mobile phone to buy, in order to be certain of being able to synchronise with KDE Kontact.  Oh, if only life under Linux was that simple.  I believe the best solution is to replace our mail server with an Cyrus IMAP server and implement Funambol, and aim to synchronise the mobile phones with that.  To that end I referred him to the following page:

   * http://www.funambol.com/solutions/devices.php

His preferred solution would be an Apple iPhone or possibly a Blackberry, both of which would appear to be supported under Funambol.

</description>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bootpolish.net/pageloader.pl?page=home_blog#21/06/2008: Mobile Phones</guid>
<pubDate>Sat Jun 21 00:00:00 2008</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LTSP Sound on Compaq PCs</title>
<description>
We have a number of Compaq Deskpro ENSFF P450s for which sound stopped working since our LTSP5 Upgrade.  I spent some time this  morning solving this problem and have detailed my solution here:

   * Configure Compaq Deskpro ENSFF for LTSP5 Sound

The bulk of the fix was simply changing SMODULE_01 to MODULE_01 in LTS.conf, although this particular PC was a little more involved.

</description>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bootpolish.net/pageloader.pl?page=home_blog#21/06/2008: LTSP Sound on Compaq PCs</guid>
<pubDate>Sat Jun 21 00:00:00 2008</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Big Buck Bunny</title>
<description>
&#x3E;&#x3E;&#x3E;---

&#x3C;object width=&#x22;400&#x22; height=&#x22;225&#x22;&#x3E;	&#x3C;param name=&#x22;allowfullscreen&#x22; value=&#x22;true&#x22; /&#x3E;	&#x3C;param name=&#x22;allowscriptaccess&#x22; value=&#x22;always&#x22; /&#x3E;	&#x3C;param name=&#x22;movie&#x22; value=&#x22;http://www.vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=1084537&#x26;amp;server=www.vimeo.com&#x26;amp;show_title=1&#x26;amp;show_byline=1&#x26;amp;show_portrait=0&#x26;amp;color=f0000c&#x26;amp;fullscreen=1&#x22; /&#x3E;	&#x3C;embed src=&#x22;http://www.vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=1084537&#x26;amp;server=www.vimeo.com&#x26;amp;show_title=1&#x26;amp;show_byline=1&#x26;amp;show_portrait=0&#x26;amp;color=f0000c&#x26;amp;fullscreen=1&#x22; type=&#x22;application/x-shockwave-flash&#x22; allowfullscreen=&#x22;true&#x22; allowscriptaccess=&#x22;always&#x22; width=&#x22;400&#x22; height=&#x22;225&#x22;&#x3E;&#x3C;/embed&#x3E;&#x3C;/object&#x3E;&#x3C;br /&#x3E;&#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://www.vimeo.com/1084537?pg=embed&#x26;sec=1084537&#x22;&#x3E;Big Buck Bunny&#x3C;/a&#x3E; from &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://www.vimeo.com/user508904?pg=embed&#x26;sec=1084537&#x22;&#x3E;Blender Foundation&#x3C;/a&#x3E; on &#x3C;a href=&#x22;http://vimeo.com?pg=embed&#x26;sec=1084537&#x22;&#x3E;Vimeo&#x3C;/a&#x3E;.

&#x3E;&#x3E;&#x3E;---

Finally managed to find the time to watch Big Buck Bunny.   Big Buck Bunny tells the story of a giant rabbit with a big heart. When one sunny day three rodents rudely harass him, something snaps, and...

   * http://www.bigbuckbunny.org/

It&#x27;s not *quite* Pixar, but it&#x27;s definitely impressive for a volunteer project using free open-source software.  Superb.

</description>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bootpolish.net/pageloader.pl?page=home_blog#19/06/2008: Big Buck Bunny</guid>
<pubDate>Thu Jun 19 00:00:00 2008</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sound problem fixed</title>
<description>
It transpired that rdesktop uses /dev/dsp which is incompatible with alsa.  Specifying &#x22;oss&#x22; as the sound driver, instead of the default, worked fine.


&#x3C;pre&#x3E;
  $ padsp rdesktop -r sound:local:oss 192.168.0.1
&#x3C;/pre&#x3E;


This is apparently because rdesktop version 1.5 does not support alsa, but still uses /dev/dsp as the sound device.  A new version 1.6 of rdesktop is now available (albeit not in the debian etch or etch-backports repositories), which should address this issue.  Unfortunately we are using a patched version of rdesktop, provided by fontis, and I know they were struggling to integrate their patches into the latest versions.  I should probably attempt to contact them at some point.

This also represented my first attempt at using IRC #ltsp - which proved invaluable.  Installed Konversation, as I could not get on with Kirc.

</description>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bootpolish.net/pageloader.pl?page=home_blog#18/06/2008: Sound problem fixed</guid>
<pubDate>Wed Jun 18 00:00:00 2008</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>LTSP sound in rdesktop sessions</title>
<description>
Today I discovered that since our upgrade to LTSP5, sound has stopped working in rdesktop sessions.  Worse, it bombs users out of their Windows session with the error:


&#x3C;pre&#x3E;
  rdesktop: pcm_params.c:2351: sndrv_pcm_hw_params: Assertion `err &#x3E;= 0&#x27; failed.
  Aborted
&#x3C;/pre&#x3E;


Under 4.2 it was working beautifully simply by prefixing rdesktop with esddsp, 
e.g...

&#x3C;pre&#x3E;
  $ esddsp rdesktop -r sound:local 192.168.0.1
&#x3C;/pre&#x3E;

... but removing esddsp or replacing with padsp causes exactly the same error 
message.  I suspect with alsa the esddsp/padsp fix is no longer required, but 
why does it not work?

I have even tried pointing padsp at the client pulseaudio device...


&#x3C;pre&#x3E;
  $ padsp -d -s 192.168.0.41:4713 -n rdesktop rdesktop -r sound:local 192.168.0.1
&#x3C;/pre&#x3E;


I have posted this as a question on the LTSP Mailing List and am hopeful of a solution!

</description>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bootpolish.net/pageloader.pl?page=home_blog#17/06/2008: LTSP sound in rdesktop sessions</guid>
<pubDate>Tue Jun 17 00:00:00 2008</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>